# Angela Andronova

**Technical Writer** 

**+90 545 188 2439** 

@ exebeeche@icloud.com

Phttps://github.com/exebeeche

Turkey, Antalya

SUMMARY

Highly organized and proactive Technical Writer with 15+ years of experience crafting end-user and developer documentation. Dedicated and passionate about technical writing using the Docs-as-Code approach and DocOps tools. Excellent ability with editing, reviewing, and adjusting content based on user feedback.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Technical Writer**

Status.im

Status.im is a mobile Ethereum OS that gives users the power to chat, transact, and access a world of DApps on the decentralized web

- Contributed to the user documentation repo
- Took part in software testing
- Planned the content structure
- Stack: Mkdocs Material&Markdown

## Team Lead

Arenadata Software

**1** 07/2021 - 06/2022

Remote

Arenadata creates a single enterprise data platform using open source solutions such as Apache Hadoop, Greenplum, Apache Kafka, ClickHouse, PostgreSQL

- Led and managed a team of up to 6 technical writers
- Wrote, together with my team, 100% of the new technical content for the company's Apache Hadoop-based product in 4 months
- Built a content architecture and managed design works for the documentation portal
- Stack: Antora&Asciidoc

### **Technical Writer**

SberDevices

**10/2020 - 07/2021** 

SberDevices focuses on smart devices and everything about it like speech technologies, face and voice biometrics, neural networks, and more

- Created developer guides (API/SDK) for a speech recognition service
- Participated in work for developer site layout using Strapi CMS
- Researched and developed a concept description of a voice biometrics service
- Stack: Gatsby&Markdown

### **Technical Writer**

Waves Enterprise

**1** 04/2019 - 10/2020

Remote

Waves Enterprise develops and supports a hybrid blockchain that combines both private and public permissioned blockchain technologies

- Developed end-user product documentation in an agile environment while meeting 100% of team deadlines
- Actualized and supported docs, writing to publishing, on a company's
- Increased the user documentation library by 50%
- Stack: sphinx&rST

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master's Degree - Space Geodesy

Moscow State University of Geodesy and Cartography



**SKILLS** 

Doc tools

Docusaurus API/SDK docs Markdown

DITA/DocBook

VSCode/IntelliJ IDE

Read The Docs

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Management and internal tools

Confluence

Notion

Slack/Discord

GitHub/GitLab

Infrastructure & Operations

**Jenkins** 

Docker

AWS VM

Console

Basic proficiency

Blockchain

Apache Hadoop

SQL

Spark

Figma

Scala

Swagger

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**



## Arenadata, documentation portal

The portal was built in 4 months using the Antora&ASCIIDoc stack. My team and I have planned all content architecture, design elements and navigation.



#### Arenadata, Yadro, Building TW team

I built a TW team 2 times in the last 5 years. I was responsible for hiring and establishing all processes.

## **CONFERENCES**



## **DITA-OT Day Conference**

November 4, 2018, Rotterdam, Netherlands A conference dedicated to the DITA Open Toolkit project



#### Write the Docs Conference

October 3-4, 2021, Online The conference focused on all topics related to software documentation

## LANGUAGES

**English** 

Proficient